RAJASHREE KAMALAKANNAN

www.linkedin.com/in/rajashree-kamalakannan| rajashree.kamalakannan@utdallas.edu | https://github.com/rajashreekamalakannan 7575 Frankford Road, 3421, Dallas, TX | (510) 902-9029

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Proficient in data structures and in designing algorithms with nearly 2 years of industry experience. Actively looking for an Internship opportunity in the field of Software engineering, full stack development, web development where I can utilize my knowledge and engineering skills to model and solve real-world problems thus contributing to organizations growth.

EDUCATION

University of Texas at Dallas, US

Masters in Computer Science | CGPA: 3.56

Expected May 2021

Coursework: Machine Learning, Database Design, Algorithm analysis and Data structures

Thiagarajar College, Anna University, India

Bachelors in Computer Science and Engineering | CGPA: 8.56

Jul 2013-May 2017

Coursework: Data structures, Object Oriented Programming, Software Engineering, Web Programming, Data Mining concepts and techniques

SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

Programming Languages: Java, C++, C, JavaScript, HTML5, SQL, Python

Databases: OracleDB, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, SQLite

Tools, Frameworks & Servers: NetBeans, Apache Maven, Jenkins, Git, Jira, Bitbucket, Android Studio, Spring, Angular 4

Domain Knowledge: Database design, Data structures and Algorithm analysis, Web Programming

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Associate Engineer | AstraZeneca Pharma India Ltd, India

Jan 2018-Jun 2019

- Automated the study loading manual process in an adverse event tracking application using Java which eliminated nearly 900 to 990 hours of FTE in a year with 86% efficiency in performance.
- Developed end to end modules as a part of converting a legacy application to Spring framework and Angular4.
- Deployed nearly 40 studies using Git and Jenkins into the application which manages the data flow and tracks the adverse events of patients in addition to following the GxP processes.
- Tested and validated nearly 20 critical set applications after each quarterly patching.

Graduate Trainee | AstraZeneca Pharma India Ltd, India

Jul 2017-Dec 2017

Shift Roster System

Designed and developed end to end application using Java, JavaScript, HTML and CSS to calculate the shift allowance of all the employees based on their shift roster on a monthly basis and generate report.

Research Intern | RISE Lab | Indian Institute of Technology Madras, India

Nov 2015-Jan 2016

Ensemble K-Means – Modifying the K-Means algorithm for identifying the K-value automatically and combining the results of multiple random starts to have better and stable clusters

- Implemented the K-Means algorithm using C++ with a multi-dimensional set.
- Modified the algorithm such that it chooses initial random points which are far from each other.
- Validated and checked the purity of the clusters obtained.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Tesla automobile database system

Nov 2019-Dec 2019

Designed and implemented an interactive MVC architecture for manufacturing and sales sector of Tesla. SQL and PLSQL was used to implement triggers and stored procedures like salary increment for employee based on rating, identifying defective parts and suppliers for accident reports.

Analyzing similarity between tweets using K-Means algorithm

Oct 2019-Nov 2019

Performed data preprocessing on a twitter dataset, computed their similarity using Jaccard distance metric and clustered using K-Means algorithm which was completely built from scratch using python and achieved 87% accuracy.

Detecting near duplicate documents using novel hamming distance based similarity approach

Jan 2017-Apr 2017

Designed a technique which combines simhash algorithm along with a symbol table in addition to the hamming distance approach using Java to detect near duplicate documents which resulted in a 40 seconds faster algorithm than the traditional one.

COMPETITIONS, LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE & ACTIVITIES

- AstraZeneca Pharma India Ltd Best LEAN Initiative 2018
- AstraZeneca Pharma India Ltd Best code design 2017
- Computer Society of India, Student branch, Thiagarajar College of Engineering Member
- Women Who Compute, University of Texas at Dallas Volunteer
- Techutsav-15, Thiagarajar College of Engineering Event Organizer and Master of Ceremony